Michael**Leontieff**

Software Developer

Contact

04 0162 8729 michael@leontieff.net

Web Presence

GitHub Michael Leontieff LinkedIn Michael Leontieff

Technology

Front End

JS & Typescript Polymer 1, Redux React CSS & HTML

Back End

Java NodeJS

API's

Cloud Services and

Swagger2 & OpenAPI3 Docker

Azure nsumption

API Consumption Linux

Persistence and

Caching RDF MongoDB Redis SQL (NuoDB)

Theory

Language Design Cloud Architecture Cryptography Networking AGILE and Waterfall

Documentation

LaTEX & Markdown

Personal Summary and Interests

I am a motivated, independent yet team-focused software developer looking to branch out from my current developer position of over three years to broaden my skill set in a professional context. I have a strong desire to utilise modern technology stacks and tool chains to deliver scalable cloud software in a way that challenges myself and exposes me to new ideas of what the web is capable of.

My passions in the space include the ever-evolving state of the web and the evolution in programming languages and their paradigms.

Education

Grad. 2018 Bachelor Information Technology

Final GPA: **6.792**

Major in Computer Science

Minors in Mobile Application Development

and Networking and Security

Grad. 2014 High School Certificate

Achieved Overall Position (OP) of 5 Top of cohort in ITS, IPT and Graphics

Third in cohort for Math B

Work Experience

Aug 2017 - Development Engineer Dassault Systemes Australia

Full Stack Web Developer 2017 - 2019; Back End Developer 2019 - Present

Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane

Elanora State High School

July 2017 Sessional Academic Queensland University of Technology

As a member of the Sessional Academic team, reviewed and graded final

projects for the CAB230 Web Computing Unit.

June 2017 Teacher Aide Code Camp

Aiding in the teaching of programming and computer science concepts to pri-

mary school students

Awards

2015 - 2017 Dean's List for Academic Performance Queensland University of Technology

Certifies that the Student achieved a Grade Point Average of at least 6.5 for a full time semesters study, received for all full time semesters of study.

2013 National Computer Science Schools Championship Elanora SHS

Received a Credit

Responsibilities at Dassault Systemes

- One of two developers implementing and maintaining the Geoscience Data Manager (GDM). A Platform widget which allows for the import and instancing of Geoscience artefacts for use in downstream processes. This included full stack development comprised of: data model design and implementation, server-side logic to support entity versions, access control and client side UI.
- Designed UI Automation solution to enhance test automation for cross-team, multiapplication test scenarios against Behaviour Driven Development (BDD).
- As a member of the Geoscience Data Team, contributed to the design and implementation of the GEOScience Data Model to deliver a performant, persistent store for large geoscience data sets to support BHP and Peabody Energy. This involved prototyping a solution against several available technologies and optimising the data model to suit multiple KPI's.
- As a Cloud Developer, I deployed and performed maintenance on environments to support QA operations. Additionally, I contributed heavily on data upgrade and testing.

Practical Experience

Throughout university and my personal projects, I have broadened my skill set further to include technology outside of my current day-to-day development activities.

To view an overview of these projects, visit the following links:

Stock vs. Sentiment Analysis App http://leontieff.net/project1.pdf

Azure Scalable Twitter NLP Analysis App http://leontieff.net/project2.pdf